<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Web | WebJournal]]></title>
  <link href="http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/categories/web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pashka4281.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-29T01:35:31+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://pashka4281.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paul Ser]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up Mysql Replication Locally]]></title>
    <link href="http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/2014/07/04/setting-up-mysql-replication-locally/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-04T13:11:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/2014/07/04/setting-up-mysql-replication-locally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mysql Replication setup manual</p>

<p>This two tutorials helped me to solve several issues during setup, so strongly recommend:
http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.5/en/replication-howto-repuser.html
http://scriptingmysql.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/mysql-replication-creating-a-new-masterslave-topology-with-or-without-virtual-machines/</p>

<p>I decided to set up different mysql instances using virtualbox. So in my case I have:
 * host machine with ubuntu 12.04, x64
 * guest OS running inside virtualbox (same ubuntu 12.04, but 32 bit) Networking using bridge
Both running mysql 5.5
master is on host machine, slave - on virtual one.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Steps:</p>

<p>1 . Set up master mysql. 
It’s just about up uncommenting binlog location and server id lines in my.cnf (requires server restart). Make sure the binlog file located in the directory that is exists and have correct owner (mysql). In my case it is /var/log/mysql/mysql-bin.log (which I think to change later since it seems to be cleared by the OS on each reboot). For server id I put “1”
also comment out this line both for master and slave node’s configs:
bind-address 127.0.0.1</p>

<p>2 . Set up slave mysql (or several ones)
Even easier. Just setting server id variable (each mysql node should have uniq id), I put “2” for this case.</p>

<p>3 . Set up replication user on master which will be used by slave (or by all of them) to read data from master.
Login to master mysql: </p>

<p><code>$ mysql -uroot -p</code>
general form of user creation command looks like this:</p>

<p><code>mysql&gt; CREATE USER 'repl_user'@'%.mydomain.com' IDENTIFIED BY 'slavepass';</code></p>

<p>but as my virtual machine has no domain or fixed ip address I used different form to allow connections from all domains:</p>

<p><code>mysql&gt; CREATE USER 'repl_user'@'% IDENTIFIED BY 'slavepass';</code></p>

<p>and add required privileges to the user:</p>

<p><code>mysql&gt; GRANT REPLICATION SLAVE ON *.* TO 'repl_user'@'%';</code></p>

<p>4 . Get binlog details for slaves
connect to master using mysql command and then type:
<code>mysql&gt; show master status\G;</code>
you’ll see something like this:</p>

<p>```sh
<strong>**</strong><strong>**</strong><strong>**</strong><strong>**</strong><strong>* 1. row **</strong><strong>**</strong><strong>**</strong><strong>**</strong>*****
            File: mysql-bin.000001
        Position: 107
    Binlog_Do_DB: 
Binlog_Ignore_DB: 
1 row in set (0.00 sec)</p>

<p>ERROR: 
No query specified
we would need those File and Position parameters to specify on slaves.
```</p>

<p>5 . Create data snapshot from master node and push it to slaves
<code>$ mysqldump --all-databases --master-data &gt; dbdump.db -uroot -p</code>
then on virtual machine get this dump file (you can use shared folder between host OS and guest OS) and push it to slave mysql node (but before this stop slave mode -
<code>mysql&gt; stop slave;</code> ) :
<code>$ mysql &lt; dbdump.db -uroot -p</code>
then run slave again:
<code>mysql&gt; start slave;</code></p>

<p>6 . Create user on slave that will be used by octopus</p>

<p><code>sh
mysql&gt; CREATE USER 'slave_user'@'%' IDENTIFIED BY 'slavepass';
mysql&gt; GRANT all priveleges on database_name.* TO 'slave_user'@'%';
mysql&gt; flush priveleges;
</code></p>

<p>7 . Giving master’s information to slave</p>

<p>On slave mysql console run:
<code>sh
mysql&gt; CHANGE MASTER TO MASTER_HOST='192.168.1.6', MASTER_USER='repl_user', MASTER_PASSWORD='slavepass', MASTER_LOG_FILE='mysql-bin.000001', MASTER_LOG_POS=107;
</code>
after this you will be able to run slave:
<code>mysql&gt; start slave;</code></p>

<p>Then to make sure it is connected, run <code>mysql&gt; show slave status\G;</code></p>

<p><code>sh
mysql&gt; SHOW SLAVE STATUS\G
*************************** 1. row ***************************
             Slave_IO_State: Waiting for master to send event
                Master_Host: 192.168.1.6
                Master_User: repl_user
                Master_Port: 3306
              Connect_Retry: 3
            Master_Log_File: mysql-bin.000001
        Read_Master_Log_Pos: 107
             Relay_Log_File: mysql-relay-bin.005
              Relay_Log_Pos: 548
      Relay_Master_Log_File: mysql-bin.005
           Slave_IO_Running: Yes
          Slave_SQL_Running: Yes
            Replicate_Do_DB:
        Replicate_Ignore_DB:
         Replicate_Do_Table:
     Replicate_Ignore_Table:
    Replicate_Wild_Do_Table:
Replicate_Wild_Ignore_Table:
                 Last_Errno: 0
                 Last_Error:
               Skip_Counter: 0
        Exec_Master_Log_Pos: 79
            Relay_Log_Space: 552
            Until_Condition: None
             Until_Log_File:
              Until_Log_Pos: 0
         Master_SSL_Allowed: No
         Master_SSL_CA_File:
         Master_SSL_CA_Path:
            Master_SSL_Cert:
          Master_SSL_Cipher:
             Master_SSL_Key:
      Seconds_Behind_Master: 8
</code></p>

<p>Here two lines indicates that everything is ok:</p>

<p><code>Slave_IO_Running: Yes</code></p>

<p><code>Slave_SQL_Running: Yes</code></p>

<p>If it is not, then they will contain error message.</p>

<p>8 . Setup octopus config
octopus config is located inside config/shards.yml file.
in my case virtual machine has address 192.168.1.12 in my local network so putting this address inside config as well as user data from step 6: </p>

<p><code>sh
octopus:
  environments:
    - development
    - production
  replicated: true
  fully_replicated: true 
  development:
    slave1:
      host: 192.168.1.12
      adapter: mysql2
      database: database_name
      username: slave_user
      password: slavepass
      reconnect: false
</code></p>

<p>Now we can run rails server and it should connect to all databases automatically.
The log from rails app looks like this if everything correct:</p>

<p>[Shard: slave1]  User Load (1.5ms)  SELECT <code>users</code>.* FROM <code>users</code> WHERE <code>users</code>.<code>remember_token</code> = ‘065c1bf9e95585b240e682cb380accee50551544’ LIMIT 1
  Rendered layouts/_header.html.erb (3.2ms)
  Rendered layouts/_messages.html.erb (0.2ms)
  Rendered layouts/_footer.html.haml (0.9ms)
Completed 200 OK in 57ms (Views: 49.4ms | ActiveRecord: 6.2ms)</p>

<p>Note <code>[Shard: slave1]</code> that indicates which shard (slave) was used to get data from.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node JS Ecosystem From Rails Developer Perspective - Part1]]></title>
    <link href="http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/2014/06/01/node-js-ecosystem-from-rails-developer-perspective-part1/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-01T04:50:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/2014/06/01/node-js-ecosystem-from-rails-developer-perspective-part1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That was a rainy night of Saturday when I was sitting down and reading some blog I found a notice about Node. Yay, now I know how to spend rest of the eve - I thought :)</p>

<p>Honestly saying, some time ago I have already made “first steps” in writing server side js using node, but that was so long ago so I decided to try again and go further that first time.</p>

<p>So let’s start from installing npm (node package manager - similar to gem from rails). I had it already installed but for those who just starting follow next steps (quote taken from ubuntu community).
<!-- more --></p>

<h2 id="step-1---installing-node">Step 1 - installing node</h2>

<p>Those are pretty easy and not involving compiling stuff:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You can use this node.js PPA:</p>

  <p><code>ppa:chris-lea/node.js</code></p>

  <p>If you’re on Ubuntu Server, first do this:</p>

  <p><code>$ sudo apt-get install python-software-properties</code></p>

  <p>Then, do this:</p>

  <p><code>$ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:chris-lea/node.js</code></p>

  <p><code>$ sudo apt-get update</code></p>

  <p><code>$ sudo apt-get install nodejs</code></p>

  <p>Then, you have the latest version of node.js installed.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Then, check if node was installed correctly:</p>

<p><code>$ node -v</code></p>

<h2 id="step-2---install-npm">Step 2 - Install NPM</h2>

<p>Simply run the NPM install script:</p>

<p>curl https://npmjs.org/install.sh | sudo sh
And then check it works:</p>

<p>npm -v
That’s all.</p>

<h2 id="step-3---creating-basic-skeleton-of-you-very-first-node-web-app">Step 3 - Creating basic skeleton of you very first Node web app</h2>
<p>For accomplishing this step I strongly recommend to use ExpressJs - a small npm package (aka gem) that boost your node app with such nice features as routing, template handling (Jade by default –  very similar to haml) and some other useful stuff. Creating server with expressjs is also simple proccessas well as configuring it. Node app has no strict folders structure (as Rails do) but it nice to have some place to start of. There are plently much app template/seed projects available out there, let’s use on of them that contains basic blog application:</p>

<p><code>https://github.com/btford/angular-express-blog</code></p>

<p>(yeah-yeah you have already noticed this seed project includes AngularJS :) – we’ll get back to it a bit later )</p>

<p>So:</p>

<p><code>$ git clone https://github.com/btford/angular-express-blog.git &amp;&amp; cd angular-express-blog</code></p>

<p>Then run</p>

<p><code>$ npm install</code> to install all the app dependencies (this is similar to bundle install in rails. This command will install dependencies described in package.json file – node analog for Gemfile. You can edit it to add required libs/plugins)</p>

<p>This should run smoothly and finaly we’re able to run our app!
<code>$ node app.js</code></p>

<p><code>$ Express server listening on port 3000 in development mode</code></p>

<p>Now open your favourite browser and point it to http://localhost:3000</p>

<p>This is what you would see, your first hand-made Node js blog. We did it :) </p>

<p><img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2906/14314489362_f2296fd5ab_b.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="step-4---application-structure">Step 4 - application structure</h2>

<p>Basically the structure of the app skeleton we have copied looks like this:</p>

<p><code>sh
README.md
app.js              --&gt; app config
package.json        --&gt; for npm
public/             --&gt; all of the files to be used in on the client side
  css/              --&gt; css files
    app.css         --&gt; default stylesheet
  img/              --&gt; image files
  js/               --&gt; javascript files
    app.js          --&gt; declare top-level app module
    controllers.js  --&gt; application controllers
    directives.js   --&gt; custom angular directives
    filters.js      --&gt; custom angular filters
    services.js     --&gt; custom angular services
    lib/            --&gt; angular and 3rd party JavaScript libraries
      angular/
        angular.js            --&gt; angular js
        angular.min.js        --&gt; minified angular js
        angular-*.js          --&gt; angular add-on modules
        version.txt           --&gt; version number
routes/
  api.js            --&gt; route for serving JSON
  index.js          --&gt; route for serving HTML pages and partials
views/
  index.jade        --&gt; main page for app
  layout.jade       --&gt; doctype, title, head boilerplate
  partials/         --&gt; angular view partials (partial jade templates)
    addPost.jade
    deletePost.jade
    editPost.jade
    index.jade
    readPost.jade
</code></p>

<p>It’s pretty self-explanary, I’ll stop only for certain moments to clarify.
The main starting point of the app is actually app.js file. it combines some <code>require</code> statements to load external libs, code for setting up express server and define some config parameters to it (e.g. templating engine, running port, routes etc.).</p>

<h2 id="step-5---expressjs-routings">Step 5 - ExpressJS routings</h2>

<p>Special quote for routes. They have some differences comparing to Rails’s. The app.js contains routes only constraints but their definitions are placed under ./routes folder. 
Instead of mapping an http route to controller’s action (like rails do) express routes defines make rails controllers job as well: they define what to do with the request (e.g. redirect it) or what data should be sent for a particular request.
Consider example:</p>

<p>We requring definitions contained in ./routes/api.js file and place it to api variable
<code>var api = require('./routes/api');</code></p>

<p>Then to map <code>posts</code> definition to get request for ‘/api/posts’ path we do this:
<code>app.get('/api/posts', api.posts);</code></p>

<p>This would work since /routes/api.js contains definition named ‘posts’:</p>

<p><code>sh
exports.posts = function (req, res) {
  var posts = [];
  data.posts.forEach(function (post, i) {
    posts.push({
      id: i,
      title: post.title,
      text: post.text.substr(0, 50) + '...'
    });
  });
  res.json({
    posts: posts
  });
};
</code></p>

<p>So when client requests /api/posts via GET ‘posts’ function will be called.
The common format of the route definition fuction is
<code>function(req, res){ ... }</code></p>

<p>Req and res objects stands for Request and Response respectively. They have plently on methods to deal with request and response, but in our case we want to render json, this goal is accomplished by calling json function on res object and passing desired json as an argument:</p>

<p><code>function(req, res){ res.json({ foo: "bar" }) }</code></p>

<p>This way you can easily create json API for your client side code.
Another way of using routes - rendering templates. Example from our app you can inspecting <code>./routes/index.js</code> file.
Similar to rendering json but using ‘render’ function on res object:</p>

<p><code>sh
function(req, res){
  res.render('index');
};
</code></p>

<p>It would pick up and render template ‘index.jade’ under ./views folder.</p>

<h2 id="step-6---jade-templates">Step 6 - Jade templates</h2>
<p>More detailed info about jade templating language can be found here http://jade-lang.com/
It has similar to haml syntax so if you know how to write haml you’ll be easy to deal with jade. (Need to say, I’m sure you can find plugins for haml support as well).
Most important notice for us as rails developers - it supports layouts, partials and other good stuff we used to work with in Rails.</p>

<p>Jade layout should contain <code>block body</code> code. Thi is a place where templates will  be included:</p>

<p><code>sh
!!!
html(ng-app="myApp")
  head
    meta(charset='utf8')
    base(href='/')
    title Angular Express Seed App
    link(rel='stylesheet', href='http://pashka4281.github.com/bower_components/bootstrap/dist/css/bootstrap.min.css')
    link(rel='stylesheet', href='http://pashka4281.github.com/css/app.css')
  body
    include shared/navbar
    .container
      block body
</code></p>

<p><code>include shared/navbar</code> will include navbar.jade partial located inside ./views/shared folder.</p>

<p>BTW, if you’re using sublime2 as you text editor there is a simple tutorial of adding jade syntax highlighting to it:
&gt; Hit Command-Shift-P to open up the Command Palette, where you can type “install package”.   Hit enter and it will open up another search box.
&gt; Type “jade” and it should autocomplete to the Jade package.  Hit enter to install the package.
&gt; Restart Sublime Text 2.</p>

<p>That’s it for layouts. As for views, they should contain layout name which should be used for rendering:</p>

<p>```sh
extends layout</p>

<p>block body
  div.container
    Hello!
```</p>

<p><code>extend layout</code> here says that this view should be rendered under layout named “layout” :)</p>

<p>So that’s it for this post, in next posts I’ll tell you how angular works for this app, how to deal with assets using Bower, setting up database connection and even bringing some ORM functionality to you nodeJs app. Stay tuned!
Questions are really welcome :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging Web Application Directly on Your Android Device]]></title>
    <link href="http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/2013/01/31/debugging-web-application-directly-on-your-android-device/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T17:17:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/2013/01/31/debugging-web-application-directly-on-your-android-device</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you take care of how would your web app look on mobile devices this will be definitely helpful. So to make it work you need to satisfy next conditions:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Obviously, you’ll need an android device you’re going to test on (preferably Android 3.2 and higher)</li>
  <li>Android SDK installed</li>
  <li>Both desktop and mobile should run Google Chrome Browser (Chrome beta is also supported)</li>
  <li>USB cable</li>
</ul>

<!-- more -->
<p>At first, download Android SDK from <a href="http://developer.android.com/sdk/index.html">official site</a> 
then extract it’s content. I use Ubuntu and in my case SDK is located inside of ‘bin’ folder, 
right under ‘home’ foler: <code>~/bin/adt-bundle-linux-x86_64/</code>. </p>

<p>When you have SDK installed, connect your mobile device using USB cable to your desktop. 
But first you need to enable USB debugging on your mobile device, both in Chrome and system settings. 
Once you did it, you need to make sure your device is correctly detected, run “adb” tool for that: <br />
<code>~$ cd ~/bin/adt-bundle-linux-x86_64/sdk/platform-tools</code> <br />
<code>~$ ./adb devices</code></p>

<p>You’ll get output similar to this:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>List of devices attached <br />
  4df1f0377f5f8fc7    device</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So we can see device is listed correctly. Next, enable port forwarding by running this command: <br />
<code>./adb forward tcp:9222 localabstract:chrome_devtools_remote</code></p>

<p>This should yield some output, but in my case it showed nothing.
Now it’s time for most interesting! Open Chrome both on Android device and on desktop. 
Follow your desktop browser to this URL <code>http://localhost:9222/</code> and’re going to see the 
list of opened tabs on your mobile device:</p>

<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8492/8431975033_2fbe3d65fd_z.jpg" alt="img" /></p>

<p>After you have choose one you’ll see usual chrome developer tools window:</p>

<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8217/8431995941_0a6485bb3f_z.jpg" alt="img" /></p>

<p>And some corresponding mobile screenshots:</p>

<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8097/8431988489_e8190eef4f_z.jpg" alt="img" /></p>

<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8464/8431989119_1f6748d41e_z.jpg" alt="img" /></p>

<p>Now you can do everything with Chrome dev tools right on your mobile device! Yay!</p>

<p><a href="https://developers.google.com/chrome-developer-tools/docs/remote-debugging">Google Original Article with more detailed instructions on how to set up connection between Desktop and mobile Chrome</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
