<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tips&Tricks | WebJournal]]></title>
  <link href="http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/categories/tips-tricks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pashka4281.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-08T17:40:40+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://pashka4281.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Paul Ser]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Boost Your Freelancer Profile: 5 Ultimate Tips]]></title>
    <link href="http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/2014/06/07/how-to-boost-your-freelancer-profile-5-ultimate-tips/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-07T05:04:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://pashka4281.github.com/blog/2014/06/07/how-to-boost-your-freelancer-profile-5-ultimate-tips</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Working as a freelancer has huge benefints over traditional office job for sure.
Really. Think of it: you free to choose when to work, how to work, how much do you take for your work and even who to work with. Great freedom that engages you to develop your online worker profile very quickly and start taking your first orders within days. There are a bunch of online tools/marketplaces out there that will help you in that. There is a good article on this topic I’d really engage you to check out: http://www.bnewton.co.uk/blog/my-ultimate-web-freelancing-compilation-guide-how-to-quit-your-day-job-and-become-a-full-time-freelancer/. I’m sure you’ll find something interesting for yourself there.
What I want to discuss is the situation when you already have several years of freelance working experiance and you notice that your growing as a professional is not so fast as the first days of freelancing. You’ve probably asked yourself, “Is there any way I can improve the quality of services I provide thus making my client more happy and keep my rate up to date?”.</p>

<p>Thinking of it need to say that developing your online profile is much like the same as promoting any othere product/service over the web so regular marketing techniques plays well here as well.</p>

<p>Here are my thought about it.</p>

<!-- more -->

<ol>
  <li>
    <h2 id="increase-you-online-impact">Increase you online impact</h2>
    <p>Probably the most valuable item in the whole list.
Here I mean that you should’t limit yourself with having only one active online profile.
It’s a really good idea to have your personal site and blog in additiona to your Elance profile. Taking part in open-source project development or having your side project are even better. Those are great indicators for potentional clients that you really passion about things you do and open-source contribution or strong StackOverflow profile confirms your comunity-proven skills. </p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Think of your personal site as a landing page that converts visitors into clients. Developing your personal website requires much care. Especially if you’re a webdesigner/developer. This is a good place to show your skills, so spend some time to make it shine.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <h2 id="keep-your-client-list-updated">Keep your client list updated</h2>
    <p>As you works your clients list keeps growing and you probaly can’t even remeber everyone you have worked with. I beleive that your freelance success consists not only from the quality of services you provide but also depends strongly on your communication skills and building long time relations with your clients. I think many people have a big gap here. You need to keep in mind that it’s always easier to get a job from the client you have already worked with previously, since he or she already knows your reliability and quality of work. So being on-the-wire with your previous customers is really significant for you as a professional.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <h2 id="learn-last-trendscutting-edge-technologies-in-your-area-of-expertise">Learn last trends/cutting-edge technologies in your area of expertise</h2>
    <p>Developing your profile envolves continiously learning. “Spending half an hour every day on learning new tricks will make you the best specialist in your niche in 3 years” - my brother said once. Can’t dissagree with him on this point. Btw, this rule applies nicely not only on freelancing but literally on every aspect of your life: sports, health or even relations. The key part here: your sould be consistent. After all, half an hour a day not so much time to afraid to loose. I think we spend more in the our local store choosing ingridients for the dinner. </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <h2 id="improve-productivity">Improve productivity</h2>
    <p>Your work should be effective in terms of time. But there is no chance to improve something if we don’t know the numbers. Use online services to track your activity over the day and in two weeks you’ll get detailed information of the most time consuming tasks. I’d recommend to choose one of the proven tools like Tahometer (http://www.tahometer.com/) or Timely (http://www.timelyapp.com/). Also think what processes that you do on the regular basics distratcs you from your main activity and can be automated to give you additional minutes or even hours of productive work. There is a good post about automation software you can find here: http://blog.bidsketch.com/freelancing/automatic-freelance-business/</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <h2 id="keep-your-working-space-clean--organized-have-good-rest-and-dont-try-over-working">Keep your working space clean &amp; organized, have good rest and don’t try “over-working”</h2>
    <p>Sounds like an obvious thing, but from my own experience have huge influence on quality of work. As a freelancer you’re responsile of organizing your working space. If you work from homw, make sure that your hommies understands you’re working and wouldn’t distract you while you have skype conference with your clinet. Working in front of the monitor can be really hard so I recommend to to exceed 5-6 hours limit a day, and don’t forget to make short breaks every hour to give your eyes rest. Spend those time away from your laptop. This would help you feel good  by the end of the day :)</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Thanks to everyone read this post, hope you found something useful here and feel free to ask questions in the comments below. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
